The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high-quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: So did everyone turn in PSET1?
教授：那么每个人都上交PSET1吗？
Yes?
是？
Good.
好。
OK, so there is a PSET1 critique due in a few days.
好的，几天后将有一个PSET1评论。
My advice?
我的建议？
You already did PSET1.
您已经做过PSET1。
You remember what you wrote out on the proof.
您还记得您在证明上写的内容。
Look at the solution.
查看解决方案。
Write one paragraph today, and you're done with it.
今天写一个段落，就完成了。
Then you go focus on PSET2.
然后，您将重点放在PSET2上。
If you leave it off until Tuesday,
如果您推迟到周二，
you're going to have to read your proof again,
您将不得不再次阅读证明，
remember what you're thinking.
记住你在想什么。
It's a lot more work.
还有很多工作要做。
Just do it now, get it out of the way,
现在就做，摆脱它，
and put PSET1 behind you.
并把PSET1放在你身后。
AUDIENCE: Is the critique only for the proof?
听众：批评只是为了证明？
Or is this for all of them?
还是所有这些都适合？
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
Just the proof.
只是证明。
So you have to compare your proof with our proof?
因此，您必须将您的证明与我们的证明进行比较？
AUDIENCE: Is there an assignment for that?
听众：是否有作业？
Or do we just know to do it?
还是我们只知道这样做？
PROFESSOR: Uh.
教授：嗯。
PSET1 be Stellar.
PSET1是恒星。
Oh, no, sorry.
哦，不，对不起。
It's not in Stellar.
它不在恒星中。
It's on our new grading site that just went out.
只是在我们刚刚发布的新评分网站上。
So you have to go to our new grading site,
因此，您必须转到我们的新评分网站，
and you have to type in your critique there.
而且您必须在此处输入您的评论。
And it's one paragraph.
这是一个段落。
You should aim for one paragraph.
您应该瞄准一个段落。
If you're doing more than that, then you're
如果您要做的不止这些，那您就是
doing something wrong.
做错了事。
And it's LATEX Plus math mode.
这是LATEX Plus数学模式。
So you can use math mode, and that's about it.
因此，您可以使用数学模式，仅此而已。
OK, any more questions about the critique?
好吧，关于评论还有其他问题吗？
It's a new thing.
这是新事物。
We care about it because it will make our grading life easier.
我们很在意它，因为它会使我们的分级生活变得更加轻松。
And because it'll force you to look at the solutions and see
而且因为它会迫使您查看解决方案并查看
what you understood and what you didn't.
你了解什么，你不了解什么。
So we care about it.
因此，我们关心它。
Don't ignore it.
不要忽略它。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Like, how much is it weighted?
听众：像，它加权了多少？
How much does it count toward the grade?
多少计入年级？
PROFESSOR: If you don't have a critique,
教授：如果您没有批评意见，
we will most likely give you a 0 for proof.
我们很可能会给您0作为证明。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: If your proof is bad and your critique of the proof
教授：如果您的证明不正确，并且您对证明的批评
is good, then you might get something.
是好的，那么你可能会得到一些。
If your proof is bad and you have no critique--
如果您的证明不正确，并且没有批评意见，
actually if your proof is whatever it is and you
实际上，如果您的证明是事实，并且您
have no critique, you get a 0.
没有评论，您得到0。
AUDIENCE: Yeah. [CHUCKLE]
听众：是的。 [笑声]
PROFESSOR: Any more questions about that?
教授：还有其他问题吗？
OK.
好。
Who needs help remembering what the document distance
谁需要帮助记住文档距离
problem is?
问题是？
OK.
好。
Everyone who went to lecture or to [INAUDIBLE] remembers.
参加演讲或[听不清]的每个人都记得。
That's good.
那很好。
Who went to lecture last time?
上次谁去讲课？
Cool.
凉。
That's good.
那很好。
So we did insertion sort and merge sort
所以我们做了插入排序和合并排序
from a theoretical standpoint.
从理论上讲。
Today we're going to look at the code for the insertion sort
今天，我们将看一下插入排序的代码
and, if we have time, look at the code for merge-sort,
如果有时间，请查看合并排序的代码，
and use the same strategy as we did last time to analyze them,
并使用与上次分析时相同的策略，
look at the running time, make sure the running time matches
查看运行时间，确保运行时间匹配
the theory, and see how pseudocode turns into Python.
理论，并了解伪代码如何变成Python。
So you all have your listings.
所以大家都有您的清单。
Last time in document distance, we covered Main,
上次是文档距离，我们介绍了Main，
and we covered most of the functions
我们涵盖了大多数功能
except for count frequency.
除了计数频率。
Can anyone remind me what the call graph looked like?
谁能提醒我调用图的样子？
So the call graph is the tree that I
所以调用图就是我的树
had up on the left, and it started at Main.
在左上方，它从Main开始。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So Main calls word frequencies for file, which in turn calls?
那么Main调用文件的单词频率，哪个依次调用？
AUDIENCE: Well, it's probably line list.
听众：嗯，可能是线路清单。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: And count frequency.
听众：并计算频率。
PROFESSOR: So we pretend we don't see the read file called.
教授：所以我们假装看不到读取的文件。
We assume that the data is already in memory
我们假设数据已经在内存中
or that the call takes time that's
或通话需要花费时间
proportional to the running-- to the length of the file.
与文件的长度成正比。
And we only look at get-word from line list and count
我们只看行列表中的获取单词并计数
frequency.
频率。
OK.
好。
Who else does Main call?
Main还打电话给谁？
AUDIENCE: Vector angle?
听众：矢量角？
PROFESSOR: And the vector angle?
教授：矢量角？
AUDIENCE: Inner product.
受众：内部产品。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Let's put up the constants for-- for the document distance
让我们为文档距离设置常量
problem that we used last time.
我们上次使用的问题。
So we said that the document has W words.
所以我们说文件有W字。
And then when you take that list of words
然后当你把那个单词列表
and you turn it into a distance vector,
然后把它变成距离矢量
you will get assigned to a document vector.
您将被分配到文档向量。
You will get L elements, which basically means L unique words.
您将获得L个元素，这基本上意味着L个唯一词。
So L is the document vector length.
所以L是文档向量长度。
And we assume we're using a natural language like English,
我们假设我们使用的是自然语言，例如英语，
so all the words are bounded in size.
因此所有单词的大小都有限制。
Like 5 to 10 characters, for example.
例如5到10个字符。
And to make our life easier, we say
为了使我们的生活更轻松，我们说
all the words have the same size W. So w is the word length.
所有的单词都具有相同的大小W。因此w是单词长度。
Using these numbers, can anyone remind me
使用这些数字，谁能提醒我
what we said the costs for these methods are?
我们说这些方法的成本是多少？
And we didn't analyze count frequency,
而且我们没有分析计数频率
so it's OK to not take my word for it
所以不要相信我的话
and not tell me what I said last time.
不要告诉我我上次说的话
But I would like numbers for word frequencies from file,
但是我想从文件中获取单词频率的数字，
get word from line list, vector angle, and inner product.
从行列表，矢量角度和内积中获取单词。
AUDIENCE: Was that mu squared?
听众：那个亩平方吗？
That was last time.
那是最后一次。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Which-- which one?
哪个-哪个？
Does anyone-- does anyone else want to try?
是否有人-其他人想要尝试吗？
Let's not do guessing.
我们不要猜测。
I'll pull them up if nobody remembers.
如果没人记得，我会把它们拉起来。
I spent an entire hour on that, and you guys did too.
我花了整整一个小时，你们也做了。
It was painful.
真痛苦
AUDIENCE: I know.
听众：我知道。
But we had to, like, you know, add them up, and then--
但是我们必须像您所知道的那样将它们加起来，然后-
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So we did a lot of work for those numbers.
因此，我们为这些数字做了很多工作。
So get word from line list was order of W squared.
因此从行列表中得到单词是W的平方。
Does anyone remember why?
有谁记得为什么？
What made it take so much time?
是什么导致了这么长时间？
AUDIENCE: 'Cause you append it to the word list.
听众：因为您将它附加到单词列表中。
For, like, you add it to the end to go through.
例如，您可以将其添加到末尾进行操作。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So you add it.
因此，您添加了它。
So what?
所以呢？
AUDIENCE: So, like, every time you need it,
听众：因此，就像您每次需要时一样，
you, like, do word list equals word list plus words in line.
您喜欢单词列表等于单词列表加上行中的单词。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So get words from line list, line five.
因此，从第五行的行列表中获取单词。
There's a plus there.
有一个加号。
And that plus sign messes up the performance.
那个加号会破坏性能。
So that's why it's w squared.
这就是为什么它平方的原因。
Count frequency, we didn't cover it,
计算频率，我们没有涵盖它，
you had to take my word for it.
你必须相信我的话。
So we will cover it now.
因此，我们现在将进行介绍。
And, inner product.
而且，内部产品。
So suppose you have two vectors of line-- length L1 and L2.
因此，假设您有两个线向量-长度L1和L2。
How much time does it take to compute the inner product?
计算内积需要多少时间？
AUDIENCE: L1, L2 time.
听众：L1，L2时间。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So how much time does vector angle take?
那么矢量角度需要多少时间？
AUDIENCE: L1 L2 time.
听众：L1 L2时间。
PROFESSOR: L1 L2.
教授：L1 L2。
So it makes three calls, right?
这样就打了三个电话，对不对？
You get the two things.
您得到两件事。
First, it computes the inner product of the two lists.
首先，它计算两个列表的内积。
And then it has to compute the inner product of each vector--
然后它必须计算每个向量的内积
of each document vector with itself.
每个文档向量本身。
Because that's what's on the bottom of the fraction.
因为那是分数的底部。
So what's the running time for that?
那么，这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: Plus L1 squared, plus L2 squared.
听众：加L1平方，加L2平方。
PROFESSOR: Plus L1 squared, plus L2 squared.
教授：加L1平方，加L2平方。
So someone was really helpful last time and asked me,
所以上次有人真的很有帮助，问我，
can you make this simpler with some math?
您可以通过一些数学使它更简单吗？
And I said, I don't know so I don't think I will.
我说，我不知道，所以我认为我不会。
But I looked at-- my, I looked at my high school math
但是我看着-我看着高中数学
afterwards, and it turns out that these-- so L1 squared
之后，事实证明这些-所以L1平方
plus L2 squared are guaranteed to be greater than L1 L2
加上L2平方保证大于L1 L2
as long as these numbers are positive.
只要这些数字为正。
And we're working with document list,
我们正在处理文件清单，
so they're always positive.
所以他们总是很积极的。
So this will go away.
因此，这将消失。
So let's assume count frequency is w squared or smaller.
因此，假设计数频率为w平方或更小。
So the total running time for word frequencies from file
因此，文件中单词频率的总运行时间
is w squared.
w平方。
What's the running time for everything?
一切的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Would just be, like, w squared
听众：就像
plus L1 squared plus L2 squared?
加L1平方加L2平方？
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: Actually, it depends on which one's greater, right?
听众：实际上，取决于哪个更大，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, almost.
教授：好吧，差不多。
So here W works, assuming you get one document with W words.
因此，这里W工作，假设您得到一个包含W个单词的文档。
But word frequencies from files is called twice, once
但是文件中的单词频率被调用两次，一次
for each document.
对于每个文档。
First document has W1 words, second document has W2 words.
第一个文档具有W1个单词，第二个文档具有W2个单词。
So what's the running time?
那么，运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: W1 squared plus W2 squared.
听众：W1平方加W2平方。
PROFESSOR: W1 squared plus W2 squared.
教授：W1平方加W2平方。
So I take this, and I add this.
因此，我接受了这个，并添加了这个。
Right?
对？
Except when I add this, if I want to add L1 squared,
除了添加时，如果要添加L1平方，
I know L1 is the number of unique documents--
我知道L1是唯一文档的数量-
of unique words in the document.
文档中唯一词的集合。
And W1 is the total number of words in the document.
W1是文档中单词的总数。
W1 guaranteed to be greater or equal than L1,
W1保证大于或等于L1，
so it's going to dominate.
因此它将占主导地位。
I don't need to add it.
我不需要添加它。
Same for L2.
与L2相同。
This is it.
就是这个。
OK.
好。
You guys don't seem to remember the numbers for these.
你们似乎不记得这些数字了。
So that means I didn't torture you enough last time.
所以这意味着我上次没有对你施加足够的酷刑。
So let's do more.
因此，让我们做更多。
Let's look at count frequency.
让我们看一下计数频率。
And let's compute the cost for that.
然后，我们为此计算成本。
So what we did last time was, we went through each line of code.
因此，上次我们要做的是，遍历了每一行代码。
We thought, how much time does it
我们认为，要花多少时间
take to execute the line once?
需要执行一次该行？
And how many times does the line run?
线路运行多少次？
And then we compute the product of that, add everything up,
然后我们计算其乘积，将所有内容相加，
and that's the cost for the function.
这就是功能的成本。
First off, before I put numbers here,
首先，在我把数字放在这里之前，
what does the method to do?
该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: It takes a list of words--
听众：它需要一个单词列表-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: For each item in that list,
听众：对于该列表中的每个项目，
checks to see if it's-- you know,
检查是否是-您知道，
list of words that it's-- counted, right?
它是的单词列表，对不对？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So you're telling me what the code does.
所以你告诉我代码是做什么的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Try to look at Main or try
教授：尝试看一下Main或尝试
to look at word frequencies for files.
查看文件的字频。
So look at it top-down, and tell me what the purpose of it is.
因此，请自上而下查看它，并告诉我它的用途是什么。
What's the goal?
目标是什么？
AUDIENCE: Making a list of-- and each object
听众：列出-和每个对象
is a list with a word and a number.
是一个带有单词和数字的列表。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So big picture, I have the first document.
太大了，我有了第一个文件。
I read it in.
我读了。
I break it up into words.
我把它分解成文字。
And I have a list of words.
我有一个词表。
That's what word frequencies for file
那就是文件的单词频率
gives me-- sorry, that's what you get words from line list
给我-抱歉，这就是您从行列表中得到的单词
gives me.
给我。
List of words.
单词列表。
The fox is in the hat.
狐狸在帽子里。
And this gets passed to count frequency,
然后传递给计数频率，
and count frequency gives me, you said,
你说频率可以给我
an object, which is a list.
一个对象，它是一个列表。
Of lists, where each of them has the word
在列表中，每个列表都有一个单词
and how many times it shows up.
以及它出现了多少次。
So I would have "the" shows up twice, "fox" shows up
所以我会让“ the”出现两次，“ fox”出现
once, "is" shows up once, "in" shows up once,
一次，“是”显示一次，“中”显示一次，
and-- I need a shorter example-- "hat" shows up once.
并且-我需要一个简短的例子-“帽子”出现一次。
So it takes this and turns it into that.
因此，它需要把它变成那个。
So on line 2, I have a list L that's initialized.
因此，在第2行上，我有一个已初始化的列表L。
And then, at the end, it's returned.
然后，最后将其返回。
So I'm going to guess that L is going to look like this.
因此，我将猜测L会看起来像这样。
Line 3, for new word in word list, iterates over the input.
第3行，对于单词列表中的新单词，遍历输入。
So iterates over this.
因此，对此进行迭代。
And then, line 4 checks to see, for each new word,
然后，第4行检查每个新单词，
it looks at the list that I have under construction.
它会查看我正在构建的列表。
So exam-- for example, if I ran through all the words
所以考试-例如，如果我读完所有单词
and then I'm trying to put in hat right now,
然后我现在想戴上帽子，
I wouldn't have it here.
我不会在这里。
What line 4 does is, it looks at all the entries.
第4行所做的是，它查看所有条目。
And it says, if I can find the words--
它说，如果我能找到这些话，
so if I can find the word hat somewhere here--
所以如果我在这里的某个地方找到帽子一词-
then increment the number.
然后增加数字。
If I can't, then make a new entry
如果不能，请重新输入
and say that the word shows up once, because it's the first
说这个词出现一次，因为它是第一个
I see it.
我看到了。
So this is what the code does.
这就是代码的作用。
Now let's see how fast it does that.
现在让我们看看它的执行速度。
So line 2 initialize the output to an empty list.
因此，第2行将输出初始化为一个空列表。
What's the cost for that?
这要花多少钱？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
How many times?
多少次？
For new word in word lists.
对于单词列表中的新单词。
Cost?
成本？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
I know the cost is 1.
我知道费用是1。
PROFESSOR: OK, so we are-- here, it's a bit confusing, right?
教授：好的，我们在这里，这有点令人困惑，对吧？
We're saying that, oh, there's does iteration over a list.
我们的意思是，哦，列表上有迭代。
And each step of the iteration is constant time,
迭代的每一步都是恒定的时间，
but the iteration happens L times.
但是迭代发生了L次。
I'm sorry, not L times.
对不起，不是L次。
The length of the list times.
列表时间的长度。
How many-- how many elements are in word lists?
单词列表中有多少个元素？
I heard a very low W, so I will pretend I heard it.
我听到了非常低的W，所以我假装听到了。
Or I hope I heard W. So word list, the words I
还是希望我听到W。所以单词列表，我
got from the document, W. How about the if.
从文档中得到W。
So, it looks at the word that I have-- oh.
因此，它着眼于我所拥有的单词-哦。
This code is confusing because I forgot a line, right?
这段代码令人困惑，因为我忘了一行，对吗？
Pretend that between line-- oh, no, sorry, I didn't.
假装在两行之间-哦，不，对不起，我没有。
New word is-- new word is assigned in line 3.
新单词是-在第3行中分配了新单词。
So new word in line 3 is compared to the first element
因此，将第3行中的新单词与第一个元素进行比较
of the entry that's assigned in line 4.
在第4行中分配的条目的
So hat is compared with the, fox, so on, so forth.
因此，将帽子与狐狸等进行比较，依此类推。
And if the comparison is true, it runs line 6 and 7.
如果比较正确，则运行第6行和第7行。
And if not, it keeps looping.
如果没有，它将一直循环播放。
So line 5, the if how, many times does it run?
那么第5行，如果运行多少次？
Just the comparison.
只是比较。
AUDIENCE: W.
听众：W.
PROFESSOR: W.
教授：W.
AUDIENCE: Oh, no, no, no.
听众：哦，不，不，不。
No.
没有。
I'm thinking of line 4.
我在想第4行。
PROFESSOR: Oh.
教授：哦。
Yeah.
是的
I'm getting confused too.
我也很困惑。
So let's start with line 4.
因此，让我们从第4行开始。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Shouldn't do line 5.
不应该做第5行。
AUDIENCE: --new word, then you're not-- like,
听众：-新单词，那么你不是-喜欢，
you're not going to run through that again.
您不会再经历那个。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Let's worry about that right afterwards.
那就让我们担心吧。
Let's do line 4 first.
让我们先做第4行。
Sorry, I jumped over line 4.
抱歉，我跳过了第4行。
So, line 4 definitely runs W times
因此，第4行肯定会运行W次
because it's inside the for loop from line 3 to line 9.
因为它在从第3行到第9行的for循环内。
So everything here will definitely run W times.
因此，这里的所有内容肯定会运行W次。
But how many times does it run overall?
但是它整体运行了多少次？
So, line 4 iterates over all the entries here.
因此，第4行会遍历此处的所有条目。
How many times does that happen?
这会发生多少次？
AUDIENCE: 1 plus W over-- times 10/2,
观众：1加W胜过– 10/2，
because it's just worst case, L-- the length of L increases
因为这是最坏的情况，L-L的长度增加
by 1 every time.
每次减1。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, so I like that you started with worst case.
教授：好的，所以我喜欢您以最坏的情况开始。
Normally I would say exactly that.
通常我会这样说。
Worst case or W. But we had a different constant
最坏的情况还是W。但是我们有一个不同的常数
for the number of words that you have in the end.
最后的单词数。
So let's say something a little bit better than W. Let's say,
所以我们说一些比W更好的例子。
let's put the lower bound on it.
让我们把它的下限。
So yeah, worst case, all the words are different.
是的，在最坏的情况下，所有单词都是不同的。
But what if they're not all different?
但是，如果它们不是全部一样，该怎么办？
And what if in the end I know I have L words?
如果最后我知道我有L个单词怎么办？
CLASS: [INAUDIBLE].
班级：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Worst case.
教授：最坏的情况。
Almost.
几乎。
So, I know I have a W from the outer loop.
因此，我知道我在外部循环中有W。
For each word in the outer loop, how many times
对于外循环中的每个单词，多少次
does the inner loop execute?
内循环执行吗？
How many times do I have to go through something
我必须经历几次
in the inner list?
在内部列表中？
So I know here I have W words, suppose here I
所以我知道我这里有W字，假设我在这里
have L elements in the vector.
向量中有L个元素。
For each one of these, how many times
对于其中的每一个，多少次
do I have to go through-- So how many elements do I
我必须经历吗-所以我要多少个元素
have to go through here?
必须经过这里？
AUDIENCE: Depends on where you are, though.
听众：不过要看你在哪里。
For the first word, you only have to go through one.
对于第一个单词，您只需要经过一个。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
But--
但 -
AUDIENCE: For the second word, you have to through--
听众：第二个字，您必须-
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
But I heard the worst case.
但是我听到了最坏的情况。
And I like that, because it's easier
我喜欢，因为它更容易
to reason about the worst case.
推断最坏的情况。
And most of the time it's sort of like the average case.
在大多数情况下，这有点像普通情况。
AUDIENCE: So then, length of list-- L.
听众：那么，清单的长度-L。
PROFESSOR: The length of the list, and that's L. Worst case,
教授：清单的长度，这是L。最坏的情况是，
the first words that I see will be L different words.
我看到的第一个单词将是L个不同的单词。
And then all the words that I see
然后我看到的所有单词
will be the same as the words that I saw before.
将与我之前看到的词相同。
So worst case, the list will grow to L very fast,
所以最坏的情况是，列表会很快增长到L，
and then I'll keep seeing L L L. And I'll
然后我会继续看到LLL。然后
ignore what was there in the beginning,
忽略一开始的东西，
and I'll say L times.
我会说L次
So I know the second list is bounded by L in length,
所以我知道第二个列表的长度是L
the first list is bounded by W in length.
第一个列表的长度为W。
So worst case this runs L times W times.
因此，最坏的情况是L倍W倍。
And what's the cost of iterating?
迭代的成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: What is the difference between L and W?
听众：L和W有什么区别？
L is the document vector length, and W is the number of words.
L是文档矢量长度，W是单词数。
But isn't the number of elements in the document vector
但是文档向量中的元素数量不是
the number of words?
字数？
PROFESSOR: How about this case?
教授：这种情况怎么样？
What's W?
什么是W？
AUDIENCE: 6, yeah.
听众：6，是的。
PROFESSOR: So L is the number of unique words in a document.
教授：L是文档中唯一词的数量。
And I heard a really cool argument
我听到了一个很酷的论点
that I liked last time.
我上次喜欢的
Does anyone remember?
有人记得吗？
About L?
关于L？
If we're really dealing with a natural language like English,
如果我们真的在处理自然语言，例如英语，
how many words do I have in English?
我有几个英语单词？
AUDIENCE: Well, I think, at the max,
听众：嗯，我认为
there's actually around 250,000, but a lot of them
实际上大约有25万，但其中很多
are not used anymore.
不再使用。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So 250,000, right?
所以250,000对吧？
Max.
最高
So that's a constant.
所以这是一个常数。
If I have a document that contains
如果我的文件包含
all the writings of all the authors that were ever done,
所有作者的所有著作，
and say that's a billion words, L is still going to be 250,000.
并说那是十亿个单词，L仍将是250,000。
Right?
对？
So L can be very different from W.
因此L可以与W截然不同。
That's why we're keeping track of them separately.
这就是为什么我们要分别跟踪它们。
One W L times W. What's the cost of iterating?
WL乘以W。迭代的成本是多少？
So we know how many times line 4 runs,
因此，我们知道第4行运行了多少次，
but what's the cost of one step of iterating in the list?
但是在列表中进行一步迭代的成本是多少？
1.
1。
Very good.
很好。
Line 5.
第5行。
How many times does it run?
它运行多少次？
AUDIENCE: W times L?
听众：W乘L？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Same as line 4, right?
与第4行相同，对吗？
The if is run all the time.
if一直运行。
And lines 5 and 6 only run sometimes, but-- sorry,
第5和第6行有时只运行，但是-对不起，
line 6 and 7 only run sometimes, but line 5 runs all the time.
第6和7行有时只运行，而第5行则一直运行。
What is the cost?
费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: We can say it's constant.
听众：我们可以说它是不变的。
PROFESSOR: We can say it's constant.
教授：我们可以说它是不变的。
I like we can say it's constant, but why
我喜欢我们可以说它是常数，但是为什么
is it that we can say it's constant?
我们可以说它是常数吗？
Why don't I just say 1, if-- this is an empty list.
我为什么不只说1，如果-这是一个空列表。
This is a number.
这是一个数字。
AUDIENCE: Depends on the word length.
听众：取决于单词的长度。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
It depends on the word lis-- length, very good.
这取决于lis这个词-长度，很好。
AUDIENCE: And we're assuming that words
听众：我们假设这句话
are all the same length.
都是一样的长度。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: And?
听众：还有？
So, 1 times L W. Little w.
因此，L W的1倍。
PROFESSOR: OK, very good.
教授：好的，很好。
So we do assume that all the words are the same length.
因此，我们确实假设所有单词的长度都相同。
But unless I tell you that the length is really small,
但是除非我告诉你长度真的很小，
which I did, you can't say 1.
我做到了，你不能说1。
So, when you said we can say it's constant, it's right.
所以，当您说我们可以说它是常数时，它是正确的。
We can say, but we also have to say why,
我们可以说，但我们还必须说为什么，
or at least think why, that's the case.
或至少认为是这样。
So it's W-- we're going to use W here and when we copy it here,
所以是W-我们将在这里使用W，并在此处复制时，
we're going to forget about it.
我们将忘记它。
AUDIENCE: Can you put a top bar on the W,
观众：您能在W上放一个顶栏吗？
just so I can tell that it's not the other W.
只是为了让我知道不是其他W。
PROFESSOR: OK But you have to be responsible for reminding
教授：好的，但是您必须负责提醒
me to put that.
我把那个。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So string comparison, not constant.
所以字符串比较，不是常数。
If I have two very long strings that
如果我有两个很长的琴弦
only differ in the last character,
只是最后一个字符有所不同，
I have to go through them character by character
我必须一个个地经历
by character until I find the last character that's
按字符，直到找到最后一个
different.
不同。
Because until I look at that, the strings might be equal.
因为在我看那之前，字符串可能是相等的。
So comparing two long strings takes
所以比较两个长字符串需要
time that's proportional to the length of the strings.
时间与弦的长度成正比。
OK, so line 5 costs w, tricky part,
好，所以第5行的费用为w，棘手的部分，
runs L times W part-- L times W times.
运行L乘以W倍-L乘以W倍。
How about line 6 and 7?
第六和第七行怎么样？
I didn't ask line 6, I asked line 6 and 7 together,
我没有问过第6行，而是一起问过第6行和第7行，
because there is a trick there.
因为那里有个把戏。
AUDIENCE: I think it's constant for line 6, right?
听众：我认为第6行是不变的，对吧？
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
AUDIENCE: 'Cause it's a number.
听众：因为是数字。
And one place in the entry.
并在条目中放置一个。
We've already grabbed the entry.
我们已经获取了条目。
PROFESSOR: So the cost of running it once is 1.
教授：因此，运行一次的成本为1。
Good.
好。
I can tell you that that's the same case for 7.
我可以告诉你，这与7相同。
How many times do they run?
他们运行多少次？
This is the hard part.
这是困难的部分。
AUDIENCE: Wait, does break line break out of one loop?
听众：等等，断线会跳出一个循环吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Break breaks out of the loop between lines 4 and 7.
Break在第4行和第7行之间跳出循环。
I have a question.
我有个问题。
AUDIENCE: Is L supposed to be not in line with if?
听众：L应该和if不符合吗？
Yes.
是。
PROFESSOR: It is supposed to be where it is.
教授：应该在那儿。
I will talk-- yes.
我会说-是的。
So what happens is, that else is in line with a for.
所以发生的是，其他与for一致。
And if the for loop runs to completion,
如果for循环运行完成，
then it does get executed.
然后它会被执行。
If there's a break somewhere inside the for,
如果for内某处有休息，
then it doesn't get executed.
那么它就不会执行。
So the idea behind that is, usually
所以背后的想法通常是
use this for finding stuff.
用它来寻找东西。
So you iterate over a list, and when you find something,
因此，您遍历一个列表，当您找到某项内容时，
break out of the loop.
打破循环。
You did something, you break out of the loop.
您做了一些事情，就跳出了循环。
If you didn't find it, you can put an else
如果找不到，可以放另一个
and then say what code happens.
然后说出发生什么代码。
And you don't have to write code on your own
而且您不必自己编写代码
to check if you broke out of the loop.
检查您是否跳出循环。
So if break executes, then it's going
因此，如果执行中断，那么它将继续
to take us out of the loop.
把我们带出循环。
It's going to ignore the else.
它将忽略其他情况。
And it's going to run the loop on line 3 again.
并且它将再次在第3行运行循环。
So it's going to do another iteration.
因此，它将进行另一次迭代。
So line 6 and 7, how many times?
那么第6行和第7行多少次？
AUDIENCE: W minus L?
听众：W减去L？
PROFESSOR: W minus L.
教授：W减去L。
AUDIENCE: Like, if it's the difference
听众：就像，如果有所不同
in number of words and number of-- unique words.
字数和唯一字数。
PROFESSOR: Smart.
教授：聪明。
You gave the precise answer right the first time.
您是第一次给出正确的答案。
W minus L. Very good.
W负L。很好。
And what happens once-- what happens once this runs?
一次会发生什么-一次运行会发生什么？
Why do I know-- why do I know that the if won't be-- Oh.
为什么我知道-为什么我知道如果不是-哦。
Sorry, I'm getting myself confused.
抱歉，我感到困惑。
So it's going to run W minus L times total, right?
所以它将运行W减去L乘以，对吧？
Total times overall without this W thing here,
这里没有W总的总时间，
so I should put an arrow and say--
所以我应该放一支箭说-
Now suppose I didn't notice this.
现在假设我没有注意到这一点。
Is there another way I can get the decent bounds?
有没有其他方法可以使我达到体面的境界？
So this is the right, perfect answer.
因此，这是正确的，完美的答案。
You have this, you're done.
有了这个，就完成了。
You don't need to think further.
您无需再考虑。
Suppose you don't have this.
假设您没有这个。
What else can you do?
你还能做什么？
AUDIENCE: But we don't have what?
听众：但是我们没有什么？
PROFESSOR: If I didn't notice that, hey, there
教授：如果我没有注意到，嘿，那里
are L words-- There are L new words,
是L个字-有L个新词，
W words total, so W minus L words repeat themselves.
共有W个字，所以W个减去L个字会重复自己。
So this is how many times the if is going to be true.
因此，这是if满足的次数。
If I didn't have that, then I could
如果我没有那个，那我可以
see that line 7 breaks out of the loop.
看到第7行跳出循环。
So if that if runs once, then we're done.
因此，如果运行一次，那么我们就完成了。
We're out of the loop.
我们不在循环中。
It's not going to run again.
它不会再次运行。
So a bound that's not as precise as the one you gave me
这样的界限并不像你给我的界限那么精确
is 1 times W, because it runs, at most, once per loop.
是W的1倍，因为它最多每个循环运行一次。
Does people see this?
人们看到了吗？
So this is an easy way to cop out of thinking.
因此，这是解决问题的一种简单方法。
And I don't like to think more than necessary, because you
而且我不喜欢思考不必要的事情，因为您
have finite time on a test or in life,
在测试或生活中有有限的时间，
and you don't want to spend too much time on one thing.
而且您不想在一件事情上花费太多时间。
We covered the loop.
我们涵盖了循环。
Let's look at else and append.
让我们看看其他并追加。
I already got a helpful question,
我已经有一个有用的问题，
so I explained when the else would run.
所以我解释了其他时候什么时候运行。
The running time for else.
其他的运行时间。
Else is a flow-- control flow statement.
其他是流程控制流语句。
It's like break, so Python will keep
就像休息一样，Python会继续
track of whether a loop completed or not
跟踪循环是否完成
in constant time.
在恒定的时间内。
I'll give you that.
我给你
That's in the cost model.
这就是成本模型。
How many times does this else run, at most?
其他最多最多运行几次？
OK, L. Good.
好，L。
Perfect.
完善。
How about line 9?
第9行如何？
Loop stops here.
循环在这里停止。
How about line 9?
第9行如何？
How many times does it run?
它运行多少次？
That's easy.
这很容易。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And what does it do?
它是做什么的？
It's an append.
这是一个附录。
What's the cost for append?
追加费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: OK Line 10 runs how many times?
教授：好的，第10行运行了多少次？
What's the cost?
费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1?
听众：1？
PROFESSOR: You guys didn't listen to me last time.
教授：你们上次没有听我说。
So I was saying you have to look at the notes
所以我说你必须看笔记
and you have to practice this.
而你必须练习
Because you have to have this model in your mind.
因为您必须牢记这种模型。
So that when you're writing code,
这样，当您编写代码时，
this has to happen automatically.
这必须自动发生。
You shouldn't have to think explicitly about it.
您不必明确考虑它。
Because if you do, you're not going to do it.
因为如果这样做，您就不会这样做。
AUDIENCE: For the else, shouldn't it
听众：不然不应该
be W tim-- I mean, it would be called W times not L times?
是W tim-我的意思是，它将被称为W乘而不是L乘？
Because you want to look at the outer loop and not
因为你想看外循环而不是
the inner loop?
内循环？
So it can-- you call all-- once at the end of the total--
因此，您可以-调用全部-在总计末尾一次-
the inner for.
内在的。
Right?
对？
So, so it could be-- happen W times, maximum, not L times.
因此，可能会发生-最大次数W次，而不是L次。
'Cause the L is the for loop that the else coincides with.
因为L是for循环，其他循环与此重合。
And the else would only happen once
否则只会发生一次
for every total iteration of that.
对于每个总迭代。
PROFESSOR: OK so you're proposing W
教授：好的，所以您建议W
as the bound for the else, right?
作为其他的约束，对吗？
Here.
这里。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So I could say, hey, it runs, at most,
教授：所以我可以说，嘿，它最多可以运行，
once for outer loop.
一次用于外循环。
So it's, at most, W times.
因此，最多是W次。
This is a nice, easy argument.
这是一个很好的，简单的论点。
We have a bound.
我们有一个界限。
L is a tighter bound.
L是一个更严格的界限。
And when I got L, what happened here
当我拿到L时，这里发生了什么
was the same kind of thinking that you did earlier
与您之前的想法相同
to get this.
得到这个。
So this bound is good, this bound is tighter.
所以这个界限很好，这个界限更严格。
This bound is good, this bound is tighter.
这个界限很好，这个界限更严格。
And the argument behind this one is that, hey, this
这个论点的背后是
else only happens for new words.
否则只会发生新词。
If there's no new-- if the word that I looked at is old,
如果没有新的东西-如果我看着的单词是旧的，
then break is going to execute.
然后中断将要执行。
And else is not going to execute.
否则将无法执行。
So that's why I can say L.
这就是为什么我可以说L。
The beauty of asymptotics is that I
渐近之美在于我
can use either of the bounds and I'll still
可以使用任何一个边界，我仍然
get the correct running time.
获得正确的运行时间。
So I'm not going to fuss over it too much.
因此，我不会对此大惊小怪。
I like the tighter ones, because it means you guys are thinking.
我喜欢紧身的衣服，因为这意味着你们正在思考。
And you're looking at the algorithm,
您正在查看算法，
and you're understanding it.
并且您了解它。
But if you don't have them, you'll
但是，如果没有它们，您将
still get the correct running times.
仍然获得正确的运行时间。
So I think that's nice.
所以我认为很好。
PROFESSOR: OK, let's get the running time for everything.
教授：好的，让我们获取所有内容的运行时间。
Can someone do it in one step?
有人可以一步一步做到吗？
Then let's do it step by step.
然后，逐步进行操作。
So let's compute partial products.
因此，让我们计算部分乘积。
What are they?
这些是什么？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
W. LW.
W. LW。
L, W, little w-- with the bar.
L，W，小w--带杠。
AUDIENCE: (LAUGHING) With the bar.
听众：（笑）带酒吧。
PROFESSOR: Awesome.
教授：太好了。
AUDIENCE: W minus L. W. L, L, 1.
听众：W减去LW L，L，1。
PROFESSOR: OK, so if I add them up, this is all asymptotic.
教授：好的，因此，如果我将它们加起来，这都是渐近的。
So the biggest one will dominate.
因此最大的将占主导地位。
In general, I can just take a max
一般来说，我最多只能
instead of doing actual addition.
而不是进行实际加法。
So who dominates here?
那么谁在这里占主导地位呢？
AUDIENCE: The fourth one down?
听众：第四倒？
PROFESSOR: Fourth-- OK.
教授：第四-好。
Yep.
是的
So line 5 is the biggest time consumer in this algorithm.
因此，第5行是该算法中最大的时间消耗。
And I know it's W times w-bar.
我知道这是W倍w-bar。
So now I'm going to copy it here.
所以现在我要在这里复制它。
What did I say I'll do when I'm copying it here?
我在这里复制时会说什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So I'm assuming English five- to ten-character words.
所以我假设英语是5到10个字符的单词。
W L. And W L is smaller than w squared,
WL。WL小于w平方，
so the assumption that I had before is correct.
所以我以前的假设是正确的。
I don't have to change anything here.
我不需要在这里进行任何更改。
That is good.
那很好。
So we noticed last time, and already forgot by now,
所以我们上次注意到了，现在已经忘记了，
that the biggest problem in this whole implementation
在整个实施过程中最大的问题
was the plus in get words from line list.
是从行列表中获取单词的加号。
Suppose we forgot about it and we have this big pile of code,
假设我们忘记了它，并且有大量的代码，
how do I go about making it faster?
我如何才能使其更快？
Method one, go through every method.
方法一，经历每种方法。
Do this.
做这个。
Compute the running times, and see which one's the slowest.
计算运行时间，看看哪一个是最慢的。
Does this scale to 1,000 lines of code?
这会扩展到1,000行代码吗？
Not so much.
没那么多。
We're going to be giving you roughly 1,000 lines of code
我们将为您提供大约1000行代码
for PSET2, and we're going to ask it to make it faster.
PSET2，我们将要求它使其更快。
Do want to understand everything?
是否想了解一切？
No.
没有。
Instead what you want to do is run the code
相反，您要做的就是运行代码
through a profiler.
通过探查器。
So we have a computer.
因此，我们有一台计算机。
The computer can tell you which line
电脑可以告诉你哪条线
takes the most time to run.
需要最多的时间来运行。
So you don't have to do it on pen and paper.
因此，您不必用笔和纸做。
Whenever we can automate, do so.
只要我们可以自动化，就可以做到。
So we'll teach you how to run a profiler.
因此，我们将教您如何运行探查器。
It's in the notes.
在笔记中。
And if you look in the code outputs right
如果您查看代码输出正确
after [INAUDIBLE], you'll see a profiler output.
在[音频不清晰]之后，您会看到分析器输出。
So what that tells you is for each function,
因此，告诉您的是每个功能，
how much time does it take-- that's the total time?
这需要多少时间-那就是总时间？
And there's the cumulative time, which
还有累计时间，
is how much does it take together with its children?
它和孩子一起需要多少钱？
In this case for word frequencies from file, order
在这种情况下，对于文件中的词频，按顺序
of W-- this is how much time it takes
W-这是需要多少时间
including the functions it's called.
包括它所调用的功能。
So this is the cumulative time.
这就是累积时间。
Cumulative time is useful if I'm during runtime analysis.
如果我正在运行时分析中，则累积时间很有用。
Is not so useful if I'm looking at where's
如果我在看哪里不是那么有用
the slowness in my program?
我的程序运行缓慢吗？
Because if you look at cumulative time,
因为如果您查看累计时间，
you might see the slowness in one of the functions that
您可能会看到其中一种功能的缓慢性
get-- that word frequencies from file called.
从文件中获取-单词频率称为。
So the cumulative time for this is really big,
因此，此操作的累计时间非常长，
but the total time-- the time that's spent inside it--
但是总时间-在其中花费的时间-
is not that bad.
还不错
Instead if you look at total time,
相反，如果您查看总时间，
you'll see that the worst function is-- surprise,
您会发现最差的功能是-惊讶，
surprise-- get words from line list.
惊喜-从行列表中获取单词。
So 5 lines to look at-- hey, there's a plus there.
所以要看5行-嘿，那里有一个加号。
I remember from lecture that plus copies over lists,
我记得在演讲中，加上复制过的清单，
and it's kind of slow, so maybe I should use something else.
而且有点慢，所以也许我应该使用其他东西。
Does d remember what else we should use?
d还记得我们还应该使用什么吗？
We talked about that last recitation.
我们谈到了最后一次朗诵。
Extend.
延伸。
Document distance 2 .
文件距离2。
The only difference between it an document distance 1
两者之间唯一的区别是文件距离1
is get words from line list, line 5.
是从第5行的行列表中获取单词。
That plus turned into an extend.
加上变成了扩展。
One character turned to six, so about eight keystrokes,
一个字符变成六个字符，所以大约八次击键，
30% runtime improvement.
运行时间提高30％。
Very good return on investment.
很好的投资回报率。
Everything else is going to be harder.
其他一切都会变得更加困难。
So let's look at that line, because that line dominated
让我们看一下这条线，因为那条线占主导地位
the running time of get words from line list.
从行列表中获取单词的运行时间。
And think what's, then, your running time for it
然后想想您的运行时间
now that I have extend?
现在我已经扩展了吗？
Does anyone remember what get words from line list does?
有谁记得行列表中的单词是什么？
AUDIENCE: It gets the words out of the document.
听众：它使单词从文档中脱颖而出。
PROFESSOR: OK .
教授：好的。
It gets the word out of the document.
它使单词从文档中脱颖而出。
So it reads a document that looks like a regular text file,
因此它会读取一个看起来像普通文本文件的文档，
and it gets this out of it.
它使它摆脱了困境。
The way it does that is it goes through each line,
这样做的方式是遍及每一行，
reads the line as a string, breaks up the string
将该行读取为字符串，将其分解
into a list of words, and then combines
变成单词列表，然后合并
all those lists of words together.
所有这些单词列表。
Get words from string, line 4, returns
从字符串第4行获取单词，返回
the number of words in a line.
一行中的单词数。
Sorry, the list of words in the line, and then
抱歉，该行中的单词列表，然后
extend combines the lists together.
扩展将列表合并在一起。
Let's add some constants that we had last time.
让我们添加上次使用的常量。
I think we had that K is the number of words per line.
我认为我们有K是每行的单词数。
And Z is the number of total lines.
Z是总行数。
So this K is actually-- W over Z. No, I don't like that.
所以这个K实际上是-W超过Z。不，我不喜欢那样。
That's work.
辛苦了
So Z is K W over K. And we argued
所以Z是KW超过K。
that we're not going to talk about K
我们不会谈论K
too much, because a document needs to fit on a screen
太多，因为文档需要放在屏幕上
or needs to fit on a piece of paper.
或需要放在一张纸上。
So the line length has to be finite, right?
所以线长必须是有限的，对吧？
Otherwise, if I have a document that has 10,000 character
否则，如果我有一个包含10,000个字符的文档
lines, I can't even write it on this board.
行，我什至不能在板上写下它。
Even though it's really long.
即使很长。
So K, the number of words in a line, is going to be finite.
因此，K（一行中的单词数）将是有限的。
But we'll need it for this analysis.
但是我们将需要此分析。
So line 4 returns a list with the words on a line.
因此，第4行返回一个包含一行文字的列表。
How many elements in that list?
该列表中有多少个元素？
This returns a list with how many elements?
这将返回包含多少个元素的列表？
AUDIENCE: Could K [INAUDIBLE] words on line.
听众：可以在线上输入[音频不清晰]个字。
PROFESSOR: So even if I ask easy questions,
教授：所以即使我问一些简单的问题，
you guys have to answer.
你们必须回答。
Because otherwise I'll stall until you do.
因为否则我会拖延直到你这样做。
So 4 gives me a list with K elements,
所以4给我一个包含K个元素的列表，
and 5 appends that small list to the big list of words
和5将这个小清单附加到大词清单
in the entire document.
在整个文档中。
Before I used plus and that did something bad.
在我使用plus之前，那做得不好。
Now I'm using extend.
现在我正在使用扩展。
What's the cost of one extend called?
一次延期的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Constant?
听众：持续吗？
Order of K?
K阶？
PROFESSOR: I want to know your Python implementation.
教授：我想知道您的Python实现。
AUDIENCE: If Python did it like a linked list ,
听众：如果Python像链表一样，
like doubly linked lists, could be order constant?
像双链表一样，顺序可以恒定吗？
PROFESSOR: I like your question.
教授：我喜欢你的问题。
So if Python lists were actually linked lists--
因此，如果Python列表实际上是链接列表，
so if the name wasn't confusing--
所以如果这个名字不令人困惑-
then yes, merging two lists would be constant.
那么是的，合并两个列表将保持不变。
But then accessing one element in the middle of a list
但是然后访问列表中间的一个元素
would not be constant anymore.
将不再是恒定的。
Say I want to access element number
说我要访问元素编号
200 in a list of 10,000 elements.
10,000个元素列表中的200个。
I have to go through 200 elements.
我必须经历200个要素。
We didn't do linked lists when we
我们没有链接列表
ran it, so don't worry about it.
运行它，所以不用担心。
So they decided that it's less confusing to have
因此，他们认为拥有它不那么令人困惑
lists actually be arrays.
列表实际上是数组。
So Python lists, array in CLRS.
因此Python列出了CLRS中的数组。
AUDIENCE: That can use their storage contiguously?
听众：那可以连续使用它们的存储空间吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So when you copy, why can't you copy a block?
听众：那么，当您复制时，为什么不能复制块？
Why do you have to access each other?
为什么您必须互相访问？
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
PROFESSOR: So, you can copy a block,
教授：因此，您可以复制一个图块，
but in order to copy a block, you still
但是为了复制一个区块，您仍然
have to move everything.
必须移动一切。
So if your block is 10,000 elements,
因此，如果您的区块是10,000个元素，
you still have to move 10,000 bytes times element size.
您仍然必须移动10,000字节乘以元素大小。
And the CPU works on 4 bytes at a time or 8 bytes at a time.
CPU一次处理4个字节，一次处理8个字节。
OK.
好。
But this is the right kind of thing
但这是正确的事情
to be thinking about when you're doing the cost model.
考虑何时进行成本模型。
And this is what you want to have in your head
这就是您想拥有的
when you're writing Python.
在编写Python时。
So, good.
这么好。
I like your question.
我喜欢你的问题。
I wanted to say that at some point,
我想说的是，
but I didn't get the occasion yet.
但我还没有得到机会。
Lists in Python are not lists in CLRS.
Python中的列表不是CLRS中的列表。
OK.
好。
So with that long explanation, an extend
因此，有了这么长的解释，
is a list-- is a sequence of appends, right?
是列表-是附加序列，对吗？
If you have two lists and you want
如果您有两个列表，并且想要
to extend the first list to the second list,
将第一个列表扩展到第二个列表，
extend basically goes through each element in the second list
扩展基本上遍历第二个列表中的每个元素
and calls append on the first list.
并将通话追加到第一个列表上。
The list is length K, the second list is length K,
清单是长度K，第二个清单是长度K，
so K appends are going to happen.
因此，将发生K个追加。
And append is constant time.
而追加是固定时间。
Total cost, K.
总费用，K。
Now many times does line 5 run?
现在第5行运行了很多次吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
So what is the total running cost
那么总的运行成本是多少
of the algorithm if this is the line that dominates?
的算法（如果这是主导线）？
I don't want to do every other line,
我不想做其他任何事情，
so I'll promise that this is the line that dominates.
所以我保证这是支配地位的生产线。
What is the total running time?
总运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Very good.
很好。
K times L. And that is?
K乘以L。那是吗？
Oh, K. So I shouldn't have said K times L, sorry.
哦，K。所以我不应该说K乘L，对不起。
L is not the number of lines.
L不是行数。
L is the number here, so Z is the number of lines.
L是这里的数字，所以Z是行数。
So it's K times Z. Which means I'm using bad letters,
所以它是K乘以Z。这意味着我使用的是错误的字母，
so please bear with me.
所以请多多包涵
We'll forget about them in a minute.
我们将在一分钟内忘记它们。
So K times Z equals?
那么K乘以Z等于？
AUDIENCE: W.
听众：W.
PROFESSOR: W. So what do I write here?
教授：W.那么我在这里写什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Good.
好。
Very good.
很好。
What do I write here?
我在这里写什么？
Word frequencies from file.
文件中的单词频率。
AUDIENCE: W L.
听众：W L.
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What do I write here?
我在这里写什么？
AUDIENCE: W 1.
听众：W 1。
AUDIENCE: We have to-- put L 1 squared and L 2 squared back
观众：我们必须-将L 1平方和L 2平方放回
in.
在。
PROFESSOR: OK, do we?
教授：好，好吗？
Well, the-- No.
好吧-不
W, you want to always be bigger than L. I hope.
W，你想一直大于L。我希望。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So if I put it in, L 1 squared is
所以如果我放进去，L 1平方是
L 1 L 1, which is smaller than W 1 L 1.
L 1 L 1，小于W 1 L 1。
But I have to think about it before doing that.
但是我必须先考虑一下。
I can't ignore this completely.
我不能完全忽略这一点。
So this is document distance 2.
这就是文档距离2。
The asymptotic complexity improved, the running time
渐近复杂度提高，运行时间
improved.
改善。
Next thing that happens to make this faster
接下来的事情使它变得更快
is-- I'm not giving you the profiler output,
是-我没有给您分析器输出，
but you have to take my word for it that the longest methods are
但你必须相信我的意思，最长的方法是
count frequency and inner product.
计算频率和内积。
So what I'm going to do first is I'm
所以我首先要做的是
going to make inner product faster.
将使内部产品更快。
But in order to do that, I have to make
但是为了做到这一点，我必须
word frequencies for file slower.
文件的字频变慢。
And that is because I happen to know
那是因为我碰巧知道
an algorithm for inner product that is a lot faster, if only
内部产品的算法要快得多（如果有的话）
you can promise me that in this list, the words are ordered.
您可以向我保证，在此列表中，单词是有序的。
The words are sorted.
单词被排序。
So what happens in that list 1 is, the moment I see a word,
所以清单1中发生的是，当我看到一个字时，
if it's not in the list I add it at the end.
如果不在列表中，请在最后添加。
So the words here show up pretty much in the order
因此，这里的单词几乎按顺序显示
that they show up in the file.
他们出现在文件中。
Well, if instead I could have something
好吧，如果我可以有一些东西
that looks like-- what is it?
看起来像什么？
Fox.
狐狸。
In.
在。
His.
他的
Hat is somewhere here.
帽子在这里。
So if these words would be in this order,
因此，如果这些词按此顺序排列，
together with the word that I'm missing,
加上我想念的词，
then I can combine two lists.
然后我可以合并两个列表。
I can do an inner product a lot faster.
我可以更快地制作内部产品。
Let's see how that would work.
让我们看看这将如何工作。
And I'm already getting confused my words, so let's do a trick.
而且我已经迷惑了我的话，所以让我们做个窍门。
Let's say that instead of words, we'll use numbers.
假设我们将使用数字而不是文字。
So instead of saying "the," I'm going
所以我要说的不是“ the”
to say the is the 50th word in the dictionary.
可以说是字典中的第50个字。
So I'm going to use number 50.
所以我将使用数字50。
Because I want to write numbers.
因为我想写数字。
The numbers are easier to deal with.
数字更容易处理。
So say the first document that I have--
所以说我拥有的第一份文件-
the fox is in the hat-- as words number 3, 4, 6, 8, and 9.
狐狸戴着帽子-分别是数字3、4、6、8和9。
And they show up twice, once, once, once.
他们出现两次，一次，一次，一次。
9, once.
9，一次。
And say I'm trying to compute the inner product of this
并说我正在尝试计算这个的内积
with a document that has word number 2
带有2号字的文档
showing up once, word number 3 showing up once, word number
出现一次，单词编号3出现一次，单词编号
6 showing up once, word number 7 showing up once,
6出现一次，单词编号7出现一次，
word number 8 showing up once.
单词8出现一次。
OK, the algorithm for inner product that we talked
好，我们谈到的内积算法
about last time was, go through each element in one
大约是最后一次，遍历每个元素
of the vectors, find an element with the same word
向量中，找到具有相同单词的元素
in the second vector, and if you can find it,
在第二个向量中，如果可以找到它，
then take the number of times the words show up
然后计算单词出现的次数
and multiply them.
并乘以它们。
So here I have a 3, 2.
所以我这里有3、2
I would find this element here that has 3, 1.
我会在这里找到具有3、1的元素。
I have these everywhere.
我到处都有这些。
And I take the 2 and the 1 and I multiply them.
然后我取2和1，然后乘以它们。
So the 3s have to be the same, then I think the 2 and the 1,
因此3必须相同，然后我认为2和1
and I multiply them.
然后我将它们相乘。
And for all the elements where that's case,
对于所有这种情况，
I add up the results of the multiplication.
我将乘法结果相加。
So step one, go through each element in a vector.
所以第一步，遍历向量中的每个元素。
That's not going to get faster if this other vector is
如果这个其他向量是
sorted, right?
排序吧？
But the step of looking up the second element can be sped up.
但是可以加快查找第二个元素的步骤。
The first and easiest way I can speed this up is, hey,
我加快速度的第一个也是最简单的方法是
this is sorted.
这是排序的。
If I'm looking up three, why not do a binary search?
如果我要查找三个，为什么不进行二进制搜索？
What would be the cost if I do that?
如果这样做我要花多少钱？
So here I have L1 element, here I have L2 elements.
所以这里有L1元素，这里有L2元素。
What's the cost of doing one binary search here?
在这里进行一次二进制搜索的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Log of L2?
听众：L2的对数？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And how many times do I do a binary search?
我要进行几次二进制搜索？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So if I go through each element here
教授：所以，如果我在这里介绍每个要素
and I do a binary search, which is a nice and easy algorithm
我进行了二进制搜索，这是一个很好的算法
that I can explain in 10 seconds,
我可以在10秒内解释一下，
I'm already faster than L1 L2.
我已经快过L1 L2。
So it's worth sorting.
因此，值得进行排序。
Now, the algorithm that we use in class
现在，我们在课堂上使用的算法
takes time proportional to L1 plus L2.
需要的时间与L1加L2成正比。
So that's even trickier, and it's
所以这更加棘手，而且
going to take a bit more time to explain.
需要更多时间来解释。
Does-- did anyone understand the algorithm for class
是否-有没有人了解上课的算法
and wants to help me explain it?
想帮我解释一下吗？
Didn't think so.
不这么认为。
OK.
好。
So idea is that both of these vectors are sorted.
因此，我们认为这两个向量都已排序。
So if I have a 3 here and I found my 3 here, next time when
因此，如果我在这里有一个3，而我在这里找到我的3，则下次
I get to 4, I know for sure that 4 is not
我达到4，我确定4不是
going to be anywhere here, because this vector is sorted.
将会在这里的任何地方，因为此向量已排序。
Say I couldn't find 4, then I go to 6.
假设我找不到4，然后转到6。
If 6 is here, when I have to look for 8,
如果6在这里，当我必须寻找8时
I know for sure that 8 is not going to be anywhere up here.
我肯定知道8不会在这里。
So what I do is, I have a pointer here that remembers,
所以我要做的是，这里有一个指针可以记住
where's the last element that I have seen?
我见过的最后一个元素在哪里？
Does this make sense to people?
这对人们有意义吗？
So when I start here and I look at 3,
所以当我从这里开始看3
I have a pointer here that says, I didn't see anything here.
我在这里有一个指针，说，我在这里什么都没看见。
I look at 2, it's not 3.
我看2，不是3。
It's smaller.
更小
I look at 3.
我看3。
I found it, good.
我找到了，很好。
I do my product.
我做我的产品。
Then I go look for the next element here, 4.
然后我在这里寻找下一个元素4。
I look at 6.
我看6。
6 is bigger than 4.
6大于4。
So I know for sure that nothing below it is going to be 4.
因此，我可以肯定的是，下面没有任何东西将是4。
So I can stop right here and keep my pointer here.
所以我可以在这里停下来，将指针放在这里。
Then I go to 6 here.
然后我在这里转到6。
And I look here.
我看这里。
Where did I stop?
我在哪停了
I stop here.
我在这里停止。
This element matches this.
该元素与此匹配。
I do my product.
我做我的产品。
Keep it in.
保持它。
Now I go to 8 here.
现在我去这里8。
I was at 6.
我六岁
6 is smaller than 8.
6小于8。
7 is smaller than 8.
7小于8。
8 is equal to 8.
8等于8
I found something.
我发现了
Sweet.
甜。
I do a product.
我做一个产品。
And then I stop.
然后我停下来。
And I look at the next element.
我看下一个要素。
I know for sure that nothing here is going to be 9,
我肯定知道这里不会是9，
so I can keep looking down.
所以我可以继续低头
I hit the end of my list.
我打到列表的末尾。
OK.
好。
Whatever I have down here-- it's going 9, 10, 11, 12--
无论我在这里遇到的什么-即将发生9、10、11、12，
is not going to be in this list, because it was sorted.
由于已排序，因此不会出现在此列表中。
So I can stop.
所以我可以停下来。
AUDIENCE: How do you keep going--
听众：您如何继续前进-
What algorithm so you use to keep looking down on L2?
那么您使用什么算法来继续看不起L2？
PROFESSOR: Plus 1.
教授：加1。
AUDIENCE: So what if--
听众：如果……
PROFESSOR: I keep going down.
教授：我一直下去。
AUDIENCE: What if the left side was 3, 4, 6, 9243?
听众：如果左侧是3、4、6、9243，该怎么办？
PROFESSOR: 9,000, what?
教授：9,000，什么？
AUDIENCE: Just a big number.
听众：人数很多。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
Then you have to increment by 1 each time--
然后，您每次必须增加1-
PROFESSOR: So I'm not incrementing
教授：所以我没有增加
the number I'm looking at.
我在看的号码。
Here, I looked at 6.
在这里，我看着6。
Then I'm looking for 8.
然后我正在寻找8。
And after I found 8, I'm looking for 19,000.
我找到8后，我正在寻找19,000。
So I'm going to go down, either until I find 90,000
所以我要下去，直到找到90,000
or until I stop.
或直到我停下来。
AUDIENCE: So are you going to go down one at a time,
听众：那么你一次要走下去吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: --why not do a binary search?
听众：-为什么不进行二进制搜索？
PROFESSOR: Because if I do a binary search,
教授：因为如果我执行二进制搜索，
the analysis that says it's fast is not going to work.
表示速度很快的分析将无法进行。
It turns out that this gives me the optimal running time.
事实证明，这给了我最佳的运行时间。
If I do a binary search, suppose I have a list that's like this.
如果我执行二进制搜索，假设我有一个像这样的列表。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, all the way down to 10,000.
1，2，3，4，5，一直下降到10,000
Ugh, I can't write.
gh，我不会写。
And I have another list that's like this- 1, 2, 3, 4,
我还有另一个像这样的列表-1，2，3，4，
all the way down to 10,000.
一路下降到10,000。
1, 1.
1、1
I do a binary search, takes log N. I look at 2.
我执行二进制搜索，并取日志N。我看一下2。
I do a binary search, takes almost log N. I look at 3,
我进行了二进制搜索，几乎耗费了日志N。我看一下3，
do a binary search, takes almost log N. So on, so forth.
进行二进制搜索，几乎需要N日志。依此类推。
So this is--
所以这是-
AUDIENCE: But if your left list had been
观众：但是如果您的左清单是
PROFESSOR: Log N plus log N.
教授：日志N加日志N。
AUDIENCE: --10,000.
观众：--10,000。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: You'd have taken N time.
听众：您会花N时间。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
Well, this algorithm takes N time,
嗯，这个算法要花N个时间，
even if I have to list like this.
即使我必须这样列出。
It takes 10,000 plus 10,000 time.
这需要10,000加10,000时间。
Whereas this algorithm will take time that's actually
而此算法实际上需要花费时间
proportional to 10,000 log 10,000.
与10,000 log 10,000成正比。
You believe me.
你相信我
So, a way to look at this is to do bounds and say,
因此，一种看待此问题的方法是做边界并说，
for the elements 1 through 5,000,
对于元素1到5,000，
it's going to do a binary search for more than 5,000 elements.
它将对5,000多个元素进行二进制搜索。
So, the time-- the running time is definitely bigger
因此，时间-运行时间肯定更大
than N over 2 log N over 2.
N大于2 log N大于2
Constant.
不变。
This becomes log N minus 1 and log N.
这将成为log N减去1并得到logN。
That is a good question.
这是一个好问题。
I wondered about that the first time I saw merge-sort too.
我第一次也看到合并排序就在想这个问题。
And I was thinking, hey, I'm going
我在想，嘿，我要去
to do a binary search here because it's faster,
在这里进行二进制搜索，因为它速度更快，
and I'm going to make a faster algorithm than anyone has ever
我将制定一个比任何人都更快的算法
seen.
看过。
Well, if you do the analysis, not so much.
好吧，如果您进行分析，则不需要太多。
But you need to think about it, and you
但是你需要考虑一下，你
need to know why that's true or that's not true.
需要知道为什么这是正确的还是错误的。
So I like your question.
所以我喜欢你的问题。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So now let's get down so the plain old merge-sort
所以现在让我们开始吧，简单的旧合并排序
that everyone-- sorry, merge that everyone knows.
所有人-抱歉，大家知道的合并。
So if we go through these one by one,
所以，如果我们一个接一个地经历这些，
how many times am I going to be advancing this pointer?
我该指针前进多少次？
In total?
总共？
AUDIENCE: L2?
听众：L2？
PROFESSOR: L2 times.
教授：L2次。
So this pointer can only go down, right?
所以这个指针只能下降，对吗？
So worst case is going to go down L2 times.
因此，最坏的情况将下降L2倍。
And then I'm done with the list, return.
然后我完成了列表，返回。
How many elements am I going to look through?
我要浏览多少个元素？
So how many times does this pointer going to advance?
那么该指针将前进多少次？
AUDIENCE: L1?
听众：L1？
PROFESSOR: This one.
教授：这个。
AUDIENCE: But I thought, like--
听众：但是我想，
AUDIENCE: Then you get extra ones in between.
听众：然后您会在两者之间得到额外的好处。
PROFESSOR: What if L2 is bigger than L1?
教授：如果L2大于L1怎么办？
What if--
如果 -
AUDIENCE: Oh, right.
听众：哦，对。
OK, never mind.
好吧，那算了。
The reason I said L2 was because--
我说L2的原因是-
PROFESSOR: You're thinking after I'm going through this list,
教授：您在考虑这份清单之后，
I'm out, right?
我出去了吧？
AUDIENCE: Right, that's what I thought.
听众：对，这就是我的想法。
PROFESSOR: So, your answer works if this list, say, has
教授：所以，如果这个清单有
10 elements and this has 10,000.
10个元素，这个有10,000个。
And I go through this one really quickly.
我真的很快经历了这一步。
But if this list has 10 elements and this list has 10,000,
但是，如果此列表包含10个元素，并且此列表包含10,000个元素，
and they both start with 1 through 10,
他们都以1到10开头，
I have to say a 1 because that's a better bound.
我必须说1，因为这是一个更好的界限。
So I have to say this.
所以我必须这样说。
AUDIENCE: Could you say the opposite value
听众：你能说相反的价值吗？
of the difference between the two of them?
他们两个之间的区别是什么？
Because if you're going to stop at 1 has 10
因为如果您要在1停下来，则有10
and the other one has 10,000, and let's say
另一个有10,000，比方说
that only the first ten are actually equal,
实际上只有前十个相等
then you're going to go through that list, find all 10,
然后您将遍历该列表，找到全部10个，
and you stop.
然后你停下来
That would be 9,000--
那将是9,000-
PROFESSOR: I could say about that if I'm looking at one
教授：如果我看着一个，我可以说
case, but the magic trick is-- let's-- we're looking
的情况，但魔术是-让我们-我们正在寻找
at the worst case.
在最坏的情况下。
So worst case, if I have 10 elements,
所以最坏的情况是，如果我有10个元素，
they'll be all the way down in the other list.
他们将一直排在其他列表中。
Or they won't be there at all.
否则他们根本不会在那里。
And I have to go down through all the list.
我必须浏览所有列表。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So worst case, L1 plus L2.
教授：最糟糕的情况是L1加L2。
Let me see if I have any time left.
让我看看是否还有时间。
Nope.
不。
So, what I would like you to do is go through insertion sort.
因此，我希望您要做的是进行插入排序。
Insertion sort matches the textbook.
插入排序与教科书匹配。
Look at the definition in the textbook, look at the code,
看课本中的定义，看代码，
convince yourself it's the same.
说服自己是一样的。
Look at the running time, convince yourself
看一下跑步时间，说服自己
it's N squared.
它是N平方的。
Then look at inner product and convince yourself
然后看一下内部产品并说服自己
that this is what it does.
这就是它的作用。
Go through this line by line, see where they match,
逐行浏览，查看它们的匹配位置，
put the cost on.
付出代价。
Make sure that the cost is L1 plus L2.
确保成本为L1加L2。
And last, go through merge-sort and notice
最后，进行合并排序并注意
that merge in [INAUDIBLE] 6 is exactly the same
[音频不清晰] 6中的合并完全相同
as inner product.
作为内部产品。
So this pointer magic that I did here
所以我在这里做的指针魔术
is exactly what's happening inside merge.
正是合并内部发生的事情。
And understand merge-sort.
并了解合并排序。
Look at the textbook, look at the notes,
看课本，看笔记，
and see how they match.
并查看它们如何匹配。
OK.
好。
Thanks, guys.
多谢你们。